Finding Aid for Michigan Citizen Records
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Reporter's Notes, 1967-2015
  - Detroit Public Schools -- Bunita Jackson Foundation, 2007 (Box 41)
  - Detroit Public Schools Bus Contract -- First Student, Inc., 2009-2010 (Box 41)
  - Detroit Public Schools -- Emergency Manager, 2013 (Box 41)
  - Detroit Public Schools -- Financial Report, 1991 (Box 41)
  - Detroit Public Schools -- Financial Report, 1992 (Box 41)
  - Detroit Public Schools -- Financial Report, 1994 (Box 41)
  - Detroit Public Schools -- Financial Report, 1995 (Box 41)
  - Detroit Public Schools -- Financial Report, 1996 (Box 41)
  - Detroit Public Schools -- Financial Report, 1997 (Box 41)
  - Detroit Public Schools -- Financial Report, 1998 (Box 41)
  - Detroit Public Schools -- Financial Report, 1999 (Box 41)
  - Detroit Public Schools -- Financial Report, 2000 (Box 41)
  - Detroit Public Schools -- Financial Report, 2001 (Box 41)
  - Detroit Public Schools -- Office of the Emergency Financial Manager, 2010 (Box 41)
  - Detroit Public Schools -- Report, 2011-2013 (Box 41)
  - Detroit Public Schools vs. Charter Schools, 2009-2010 (Box 41)
  - Detroit -- Restaurants, 2000s (Box 41)
  - Detroit's Solid Waste Crisis, 2006 (Box 41)
  - Detroit -- Solid Waste Hauling, Transfer Station, and Disposal Contract, 1988 (Box 41)
  - Detroit -- Tom Barrow for Mayor Platform, 2009 (Box 41)
  - Detroit Workforce Development Department, 2008-2009 (Box 41)
  - Detroit Works Project, 2000s (Box 41)
  - Detroit Works Project -- Long Term Planning, 2000s (Box 41)
  - Dr. William McAdoo, 1989 (Box 41)
  - Education Achievement Authority of Michigan, 2012 (Box 41)
  - Efren Parades, undated (Box 41)
  - 8 Mile/Woodward Mall Project, 2008 (Box 41)
  - Election -- Detroit, 2009 (Box 41)
  - Emails to Eric Campbell, 2007-2008 (Box 41)
  - Emergency Purchase Agreement, 2008 (Box 41)
  - Eric T. Campbell, 2008-2009 (Box 41)
  - Fax Transactions, 2007-2010 (Box 41)
  - Federal Government, scattered dates (Box 41)
  - Financial Stability Agreement between the State of Michigan and the City of Detroit, 2012 (Box 41)
  - First Amended and Restated Solid Waste Supply Contract -- Detroit, 1997 (Box 41)
  - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA), 2008-2014 (Box 41)
  - Foreclosure Crisis, 2007-2009 (Box 41)
  - Frederick Douglass College Preparatory Academy for Young Men, undated (Box 41)
  - Giarmarco, Mullins and Horton, P.C., 2011 (Box 41)
  - Good Food, Good Jobs Summit, 2012 (Box 41)
  - Grand Prix Lawsuit, 2000s (Box 41)
  - Greater Detroit Resource Recovery Authority, 2008-2009 (Box 41)
  - Greater Detroit Resource Recovery Authority -- Board Meeting Minutes, 1997-1998 (Box 41)
  - Greater Detroit Resource Recovery Authority (GDRRA) Budget Document, 2006-2007 (Box 41)
  - Greater Detroit Resource Recovery Authority -- Board Meeting Minutes, 1994-2005 (Box 42)
  - The Greening of Detroit, 2008-2010 (Box 42)
  - HAL Development Corporation, 1991-1992 (Box 42)
  - Handbook for Charter Commissioners -- Nature and Purpose of a Home Rule Charter, 1971 (Box 42)
  - Hanover Claim, 2008 (Box 42)
  - Hassan Aleem and Carl Williams vs. City of Detroit and Kevyn Orr, 2013 (Box 42)
  - Harbor Shores, 2006-2008 (Box 42)
  - Health/Health Reform, 2008-2009 (Box 42)
  - Herb Strather Proposals, scattered dates (Box 42)
  - Highland Park, 2009-2013 (Box 42)
  - Highland Park Chamber of Commerce, 1994-1997 (Box 42)
  - Highland Park -- McGregor Library, 2009 (Box 42)
  - Highland Park -- Men's Forum, 1991 (Box 42)
  - Highland Park -- Right to Read, undated (Box 42)
  - Highland Park Schools, 2012 (Box 42)
  - Highland Park -- Water, 2012 (Box 42)
  - House Bills No., 6004; 4137; 2012; 2009 (Box 42)
  - House of Representatives -- U.S. and Michigan, 2008-2013 (Box 42)
  - House Substitute for Senate Bill No. 865, 2012 (Box 42)
  - Huskey Lumber, 1992 (Box 42)
  - Immigration Enforcement, 2008 (Box 42)
  - Incinerator/Emissions, 2008 (Box 42)
  - Incinerators Trash Community Health, 2008 (Box 42)
  - Jewel Ware/Wayne County Commission, 2008 (Box 42)
  - Jimmy L. Carter -- Prison Stabbing, 1997 (Box 42)
  - Judge Aquilina, 2013 (Box 42)
  - Kenneth Cockrel Jr., 2008 (Box 42)
  - Kwame Kilpatrick vs. Skytel, Inc. and Michael L. Stefani, 2009 (Box 42)
  - Kym Worthy, 2008 (Box 42)
  - Legal Matters -- State of Michigan, 2012-2013 (Box 42)
  - Legal Proceedings -- Detroit, 2000s (Box 42)
  - Liberian Literacy Foundation, undated (Box 42)
  - Library Commission, 2011-2012 (Box 42)
  - Local Green Initiatives, 2008 (Box 42)
  - Massage Therapy, undated (Box 42)
  - Mass Transit -- Regional, 2008-2009 (Box 42)
  - Maryanne Godboldo Case, 2011 (Box 42)
  - Media, National, 1992 (Box 42)
  - MGM Grand Detroit, undated (Box 42)
  - Michigan Campaign Finance, 2012-2014 (Box 42)
  - Michigan Cemeteries, 2000s (Box 42)
  - Michigan Citizen Applications, 2009 (Box 42)
  - Michigan Citizen -- Biba Adams, 2008 (Box 42)
  - Michigan Citizen -- Chase Bank, 2008-2009 (Box 42)
  - Michigan Delegates -- UAW, 2008 (Box 42)
  - Michigan Department of Treasury -- Financial Stability Agreement, 2012 (Box 42)
  - Michigan Education Excellence Foundation, 2011 (Box 42)
  - Michigan Education Excellence Foundation, 2011-2012 (Box 42)
  - Michigan Employment Security Commission, 1995 (Box 42)
  - Michigan Finances, 2000s (Box 42)
  - Michigan Government, 2000s (Box 42)
  - Michigan Labor Issues, 2000s (Box 42)
  - Michigan Metropolitan Information Center, undated (Box 42)
  - Michigan Primary, Caucus, Presidential Nomination, 2008 (Box 42)
  - Michigan Prison Information, 2010 (Box 42)
  - Michigan Schools, 1997 (Box 42)
  - Michigan Solid Waste Policy, 2007 (Box 42)
  - Midwest Black Publisher's Coalition, Inc., 1992 (Box 42)
  - Moratorium Now, 2011 (Box 42)
  - Mulligan's Golf Learning Center, undated (Box 42)
  - Neighborhood Information and Sharing Exchange, 1992 (Box 42)
  - New Solutions for Michigan, undated (Box 42)
  - Newspaper Clippings, scattered dates (Box 42)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 2008-2009 (Box 42)
  - Next Detroit, N.I., Fall, 2008 (Box 42)
  - Obama Campaign, 2008 (Box 42)
  - O'Conner, Doyle, 2008 (Box 42)
  - Parent Network -- Detroit, 2011-2013 (Box 42)
  - Precinct Info Database, 2008 (Box 42)
  - Primary Candidate Listings, 2008 (Box 42)
  - Prison -- Legal News, 1997 (Box 42)
  - Prisoner Re-entry Letters, 2008 (Box 42)
  - Public Health Impacts -- Coal-Fired Power Plants in Michigan, 2011 (Box 42)
  - Public School Academy Districts with Education Service, undated (Box 42)
  - Real Estate, 2007 (Box 42)
  - Reporter's Notebooks, scattered dates (Box 42)
  - Reporter's Notebooks, 2002 (Box 43)
  - Reporter's Notebook, 2009 (Box 43)
  - Reporter's Notebook -- NAACP GM Hearing, October 8, 1996 (Box 43)
  - Reporter's Notes, 2011-2012 (Box 43)
  - Reverend Pinkney -- Benton Harbor, 2006 (Box 43)
  - Robert A. Ficano, 2010 (Box 43)
  - Robert Bobb and the Failure of Public Act 72: A Case Study, 2011 (Box 43)
  - Roosevelt Park, undated (Box 43)
  - Save Detroit Public Schools (DPS), 2012 (Box 43)
  - Small Business Administration (SBA) Loans/Detroit, 2004-2005 (Box 43)
  - Second Amended and Restated Solid Waste Disposal Contract -- Detroit, 1997 (Box 43)
  - Sherwin Scott McMillan Case File, 2011 (Box 43)
  - Sierra Club -- Detroit, undated (Box 43)
  - Skilled Trades, 2007-2008 (Box 43)
  - Slater Enterprises, 1992 (Box 43)
  - Smith, Willie Harris -- Case File, 2013 (Box 43)
  - Solid Waste Disposal Contract -- Detroit, 1985 (Box 43)
  - Solid Waste Plans and Resolutions, 2004-2006 (Box 43)
  - Stand Up for Democracy, 2012 (Box 43)
  - State of Michigan -- Employment Relations Commission, Labor Relations Division, undated (Box 43)
  - State of Michigan 36th District Court, 2013-2015 (Box 43)
  - State of Michigan -- Wayne County Circuit Court Cases, 2000s (Box 43)
  - State Prison -- My Fifteen Year Walk, Sylvester Long, 2002 (Box 43)
  - State Treasurer -- Andy Dillon, 2009 (Box 43)
  - Story Documents -- Incinerator Permit/First Student, May 23, 2010 (Box 43)
  - Sumpter Meeting, 2007 (Box 43)
  - Tech Town -- Detroit, 2011 (Box 43)
  - Third Amended and Restated Solid Waste Hauling, Transfer, and Disposal Contract -- Detroit, 2004 (Box 43)
  - Tyron Gray Case, 2013 (Box 43)
  - Unlock the Vote/Foster the Vote, 2008 (Box 43)
  - Upcoming Calendar Events, 2009-2010 (Box 43)
  - Uprising -- Detroit Race Riot, 1967 (Box 43)
  - Urban Documents, Stories, April 25, 2010 (Box 43)
  - Watson -- Nine Proposed Resolutions to Amend the Detroit City Charter, 1997 (Box 43)
  - Wayne County, 2000s (Box 43)
  - Wayne County Circuit Court, 2010 (Box 43)
  - Wayne County -- Dissolution of a Committee, undated (Box 43)
  - Wayne County -- General Election Data, 2008 (Box 43)
  - Wayne County HNIC/Ware, 2008-2009 (Box 43)
  - Wayne State University -- Library System, 2010 (Box 43)
  - Welfare Cuts, undated (Box 43)
  - Where to Buy the Michigan Citizen, undated (Box 43)
  - Willie Smith Case, 2010-2012 (Box 43)
  - Women Prisoner Lawsuit, Fall, 2008 (Box 43)
  - Woodward Lot, 1998 (Box 43)
  - Worthy/Plants, 2008 (Box 43)
  - Benton Harbor Focus Group, undated; VHS tape (Box 44)
  - Detroit Focus Group, undated; VHS tape (Box 44)
  - Benton Harbor -- Paw Paw Street and Territorial Southwest Corner and Area, 1993; VHS tape (Box 44)
  - "In Their Own Words" -- Detroit's Public School Employees Speak Out About Reform, 2000; VHS tape (Box 44)
  - Kyong Park, August 14, 2001; VHS tape (Box 44)
  - "The Michigan Citizen on Air,", December 21, 2001; VHS tape (Box 44)
  - HOPE Telethon, 2002; VHS tape (Box 44)
  - Benton Harbor Presentation, August 18, 2003; VHS tape (Box 44)
  - Flashpoint Catherine, RE:, October 30, 2005; October 16, 2005; VHS tape (Box 44)
  - Mildred's Comments About the Fact that She Does Different Stories as a Journalist, August 11, 2003; cassette tape (Box 44)
  - Gaddis Discussion on Freman Ad and Kwame SUV and Channel 4 January 17th Interview, January 18, 2004; cassette tape (Box 44)
  - "The Michigan Citizen Speaks,", May 16, 2005; cassette tape (Box 44)
  - Mayor on Karen Dumas Show Day After Announcement, May 18, 2005; cassette tape (Box 44)
  - May 19, 2005, cassette tape (Box 44)
  - "The Michigan Citizen Speaks,", July 14, 2005; cassette tape (Box 44)
  - "The Michigan Citizen Speaks," Catherine Bankole -- Stallworth Article and W. Anthony -- Freedom Institute, August 11, 2005; cassette tape (Box 44)
  - "The Michigan Citizen Speaks," Bob Law, August 18, 2005; cassette tape (Box 44)
  - "The Michigan Citizen Speaks," Catherine Bankole and Steve Wilson -- Hendrix Loan, August 31, 2005; cassette tape (Box 44)
  - "The Michigan Citizen Speaks," Ethics -- Catherine Bankole and Greg Frazier, October 4, 2005; cassette tape (Box 44)
  - "The Michigan Citizen Speaks," Catherine and Sharon, October 21, 2005; cassette tape (Box 44)
- Correspondence (Letters to Editor, 2000-2015
  The Correspondence series (1 linear foot, 2000-2015) includes letters written to the Editor of the Michigan Citizen from its general readership, including African American prisoners in correctional facilities throughout Michigan.
  - Letters to the Editor, 2000-2014; 2 folders (Box 45)
  - Prisoner's Letters, 2010-2015; 6 folders (Box 45)
- Photographs, 1933-2010
  The Photographs series (7 linear feet and 189.2 MB, 1933-2010 and undated) ranges from pictures of famous African Americans and events on the national stage to pictures of local African American people, movements, and events.
  - Photo Archive (.ZIP file) (Box 45)
  - Detroit, A-R (Box 46)
  - Detroit, S-Z (Box 47)
  - Sports, A-Z (Box 47)
  - West Michigan, A-Z (Box 48)
  - General Photograph Files, A-H (Box 49)
  - General Photograph Files, H-R (Box 50)
  - General Photograph Files, S-Z (Box 51)
  - General Photograph Files, J-Z (Box 52)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs (Box 53)
    (many unidentified)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs (Box 54)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs (Box 55)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs (Box 56)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs (Box 57)